Krishan Vijayakumar

Mobile: +65 8482 1471 Email: krishanvj@pm.me

Telegram: @krishvyy Skype: krishanvj

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/krishanvj/

GitHub: https://github.com/KrishyV



Personal Statement

I have been a technologist since my early teenage years. I was first drawn into the world of technology through my interest in video games and built my own gaming computer when I was 14. Ever since then, I grew passionate about tinkering with my machine to maximize performance, writing macros and upgrading my hardware with what little I could afford with my allowance back then. My first venture into programming came when I joined a programming class in junior college (16-18 years old).

During my 2 years of service in the Singapore Armed Forces, I had the chance to work intimately with the Leopard 2 which fueled my interest in mechanical engineering, hence my choice of major.

After leaving the military, I found employment at a retail store near my house selling lifestyle accessories. During my time manning the store, I found quite a fair bit of free time, so I began writing scripts to automate some of my work. My scripts caught the attention of my manager who was keen on digitalizing more of their operations. They promoted me and I began a career in writing software. I taught myself most of my programming that I know from reading documentations and progressed from writing scripts to mobile and web applications for them in 2 years.

I am constantly on the lookout for new opportunities to hone my skills as a developer. I do write applications in new languages and frameworks from time to time both for my own learning and entertainment. My internship at StaffAny which is an early stage HR-tech startup taught me a great deal about software engineering principles and working in a collaborative environment. I can adapt to new environments quickly such as when COVID struck and my on-site internship became a remote internship. My time as a remote intern made me adept in using collaborative tools for engineers like LiveShare and Tmate.

My academic training as a mechanical engineer has made me adept in Mathematics, design thinking and problem solving. I have always preferred working over academia which explains why I have been working throughout the duration of my undergraduate years. I believe the real learning happens out in the industry; building tools and applying your academic training whenever possible to alleviate real-life problems. I am looking to broaden my horizons and work together with other like-minded-individuals in solving problems faced by their business/community.

Thank you for reviewing my application. I have enclosed my resume for your consideration. I look forward to hearing from you and would love to get in touch to discuss my suitability for your company. I can be contacted via email, Telegram, LinkedIn and mobile.

Education

Aug 2018 - Present	National University of Singapore Bachelor of Engineering (Honours) in Mechanical Engineering	Singapore
Jan 2014 - Dec 2016	 Innova Junior College Singapore-Cambridge General Certificate of Education Advanced Level 	Singapore
Work Experience		
Sept 2020 - Present	 eDealer Private Limited Flexi Software Engineer Currently building a mobile application based on Flutter to manage retail inventory top ups and inbounding of stock. Overseeing the company's transition from on-site servers to AWS 	Singapore
Jan 2020 - Jul 2020	 StaffAny Private Limited Software Engineering Intern Developed new features for both web and mobile using React/React Native. Learnt TDD principles and best-practices in AGILE teams. Served as a feature lead for several sprints. 	Singapore
Dec 2017 – Dec 2019	 eDealer Private Limited Flexi Software Engineer Core developer for an in-house purchasing management solution. Developed a performant web application based on the Flask framework. Wrote scripts to automate image processing, eCommerce orders and Point-Of-Sales inventory management. 	Singapore
Jan 2016 – Nov 2017	 Singapore Combat Engineers 38th Battalion Leopard 2 Armoured Engineering Vehicle Commander Attained the rank of 3rd Sergeant from the Specialist Cadet School. Commandeered, operated and maintained a Leopard 2. 	Singapore

Scholastic Achievements/Extracurricular Activities

Dec 2019 Certificate of Recognition @ eDealer Private Limited Singapore In-recognition of my contributions to the company in developing tools to maintain their competitive edge in operational efficiency.

Skill Sets & Proficiency

Office Productivity	Microsoft Word, PowerPoint	Proficient
-	Microsoft Excel, Publisher	Proficient

Web HTML, CSS **Proficient Proficient** JavaScript

Database PostgreSQL DBMS Advanced

Intermediate SQL

Programming Proficient TypeScript

Python **Proficient** Dart Advanced Kotlin Advanced C Language Advanced Elm Intermediate Shell Scripting Basic

Scripting AutoHotKey Intermediate

Markup **XML** Basic

Server Management & Firebase

Proficient Network AWS/Linode/Vultr (VPS Management) Intermediate

Security Wireless Security Basic

Virtual Private Networking (OpenVPN, Wireguard) Advanced

Operating Systems Linux Advanced

> Windows 10 Intermediate

Hardware Design SolidWorks Basic

Non-technical Skills Project Management Intermediate

Writing/Publications Intermediate

Language Proficiency

Spoken English - fluent; Malay - fluent; Malayalam - average; Hindi - basic;

Mandarin - basic

Written English - fluent; Malay - fluent; Hindi - basic

Additional Information

I enjoy urban skating and learning new languages; both man and machine. I build applications as a side project occasionally and am into video games and all things technology.

To whom it may concern:

I am pleased to present this letter of reference for Mr Krishan Vijayakumar. Krishan worked with us as a Software Engineering Intern in StaffAny for 7 months from January 2020 to July 2020.

Krishan worked as a full stack engineer, creating new API endpoints and database models in our Node backend as well as building new features for React and React Native apps. During the later end of the internship, Krishan took on the feature lead role in several large features, drafting the technical proposal and responsible for final delivery of the feature.

Krishan was a highly motivated intern with a good work ethic and a strong drive to learn. He started the internship knowing next to nothing about JavaScript but by the end was confident enough to write his own applications in the language. He was able to deal with the stress and cadence of working in an early-stage startup and adapted quickly to work-from-home measures during COVID-19. His independence and perseverance shone through during those times when the workplace was more isolated than ever.

I believe Krishan will be a valuable asset to any team or company that chooses to take him.

Sincerely, Jeremy Hon Co-Founder/CTO StaffAny